## Shaun Halliday

50 Windrows, Skelmersdale
07958324694 • shaunhalliday1512@gmail.com
LinkedIn - linkedin.com/in/shaun-halliday-5001a6b2
My personal portfolio site – http://www.shaunhalliday.co.uk/
Bitbucket repositories - https://bitbucket.org/24032620/

#### **Personal statement**

A highly motivated and hardworking individual with a passion for front end development and design. In the final weeks of university, so far received excellent grades across Computer Science degree, specialising in Web Design and Development and on course for a first. 21 years of work experience before university in a variety of team member and team leading roles, focusing on collaboration across businesses and knowledge sharing, coaching and supporting colleagues.

## **Key Skills**

#### **Tech Skills:**

- Experience of working in fast paced, agile environments both in workplace settings and through university, with a use of version control on projects using Git and Bitbucket
- Knowledge of Java software development through OO Java, JavaScript, Angular, React, Ember and Vue, building sites and applications and hosting sites via Netlify
- Use of kanban board through Trello use in projects to streamline and track process throughout
- BDD/TDD development to build a full stack Laravel app build with back-end MySQL relational databases
- HTML5, CSS3, Python, used to build projects and sites, through initial requirements gathering, and modelling, to enhance and distinguish requirements
- Package management tools experience with npm, yarn, gulp, homebrew, bower and testing packages through codeception
- UX modelling and research methodology experience, interacting with users face to face and remotely to ascertain functional and design requirements

### Soft Skills:

- Proficiency in all areas of Microsoft Office, including Access, Excel, Word, Outlook and PowerPoint
- Accomplished communication skills, both written and verbal, developed through previous employment, team leading, and numerous essays and presentations given during my time at university
- Through university and employment worked collaboratively as a team member, deputy team leader and team leader, taking and giving instruction to a high level (ran a whole company in the security industry)

#### Education

### **Edge Hill University**

2018 - 2021

BSc Web Design and Development predicted 1st class honours, key modules:

- Data Driven Design Team project to analyse Liverpool Museum web logs via Python, and identify and suggest improvements for website to increase engagement of users
- Fundamentals of User Experience Full individual UX project, gathering issues and requirements directly from students via surveys, think aloud protocol testing and expert cognitive walkthroughs. Following this process designed a new system and tested via prototyping expert walkthrough and reported findings.
- Server and Client-Side Scripting Laravel PHP build of a survey building app, with a
  back end for administrators to design surveys, and a front end for users to undertake
  surveys. MySQL used to build back end relational databases via schema deployment
  in Laravel. Styling implemented via Bootstrap and custom Sass.
- Usability Testing & Data Analysis Automated tool testing of a client website, determining issues and errors through performance and accessibility testing, and recoding the site to overcome these obstacles using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.

## **Open University**

## **Albany High School**

1992 - 1997

6 GCSEs, grade A-C, including Maths, Science and Double English

## **Work Experience**

**Telent Communications** – South Region Senior CSS Works Coordinator - Chorley, Lancashire

## (August 2015 – September 2018)

- Managed and maintained Openreach Candid Conqueror and CSS systems, produced and distributed multiple daily reports, both self-generated and provided by Openreach personnel and queue trawls.
- Constant daily support of colleagues across the business, also coaching team members on complex estimates and reports.
- Supported a specific area of business (London and South West coordination) building up excellent relationships with the production team, including conducting weekly calls to discuss current issues.
- My hard work resulted in Openreach remaining part of BT, and not being split off by Ofcom, due to the reduction of customer waiting times for re-connection/new connections of services.
- Also undertook project management role as part of the creation, design, implementation, and roll out of a new production software suite, with partners throughout the UK.

# **Financial Guardian –** Team Leader - Coppull, Lancashire (*June 2014 - July 2015*)

- Team leader responsible for 3 administrators and 6 sales staff which included direction, motivation and informal appraisals.
- Full implementation of dialler management software, and systems, sales software and reporting tools.
- Desk side and team coaching sessions to fully train sales and administration staff from a level of zero knowledge.
- Advising staff and managers on the Knowledge and Skills Framework and Agenda for Change process and supporting them in creating outlines.
- Participating in best practice sessions that included CIPD employment law.

**Global Guarding –** Manager - Based in Preston, Lancashire. Work undertaken across United Kingdom

(April 2013 - May 2014)

- Ran all aspects of a void property security company, hiring, disciplinary, training, rota and payment of all employees.
- · WordPress web design and maintenance for company website.
- I also undertook guarding and inspection duties of void properties across the United Kingdom which involved a large amount of face-to-face conflict management with intruders and local police services.

# **WST Engineering –** Logistics and production manager - Adlington, Lancashire (*July 1998 - March 2013*)

- Production management for CNC and welding production facilities and employees.
- Stock line picking management for warehouse staff, logistics liaison for national and international deliveries.
- Ordering of production materials, and delivery of materials, to and from international clients.

### **Hobbies & Interests**

Active interest in health and fitness, built up knowledge via fitness workshops and taking part in Muay Thai kickboxing. Interest in computers and video games from childhood, interest in sports - football, basketball, professional wrestling, mixed martial arts.